September 11, 2001. Four planes were hijacked. Three of them
reached their target. This is the story of the fourth.
United 93 is a drama, history, crime film directed by Paul Greengrass.
A real-time account of the events on United Flight 93, one of the planes hijacked on 9/11 that
crashed near Shanksville, Pennsylvania when passengers foiled the terrorist plot.
Captain Jason M. Dahl, played by J.J. Johnson.
First Officer LeRoy Homer, played by Gary Commock.
Deborah Welsh, played by Polly Adams.
CeeCee Lyles, played by Opal Alladin.
Wanda Anita Green, played by Starla Benford.
Sandra Bradshaw, played by Trish Gates.
United 93 is a 2006 British docudrama action film produced, written, and directed by Paul Greengrass, that depicts the events around United Airlines Flight 93, one of
four hijacked flights of the September 11 attacks; Flight 93 was the only plane to not hit a target, due to the actions of its passengers and crew.
The film also covers the experiences of government officials and air traffic controllers, many
of whom are played by themselves, as they witness the attacks unfold that day.
The film recounts the hijacking and subsequent events during the flight with as much veracity as possible, including using a real time
perspective where the film takes place over the exact same amount of time as the real-life events beginning from the plane's  takeoff.
There is, however, a disclaimer that some
imagination had to be used to tell the story.
Overall, United 93 was made with the support and cooperation of most of
the passengers' families, and many  attended the premiere.
There were, however, a few who did not support the film and did
not participate in any of the film's activities.
Many of the on-the-ground personnel, most notably Federal Aviation
Administration head Ben Sliney, portray themselves.
United 93 premiered on April 26, 2006, at the Tribeca Film Festival in New York City,
and later opened in theaters nationwide in America on April 28, 2006.
The film received critical acclaim, and is regarded as one of the best of 2006.
It was also a commercial success, grossing $76.3 million worldwide.
Ten percent of the gross income from the three-day opening weekend was promised
toward a donation to create a memorial for the flight's victims.
The film  received two Academy Award nominations: Best Director for Greengrass and Best
Film Editing for Clare Douglas, Richard Pearson, and Christopher Rouse.
The film explores themes of airplane, war on terror,
hijacking, terror cell, based on true story.
The tone is emotional and intense.